Bloody kids.
망할 꼬마 놈들...
How fastidious you've become, Wormtail.
그새 많이 크셨군 웜테일
As I recall, you once called the nearest gutter pipe home.
시궁창에서 뒹굴던 쥐새끼 주제에!
Could it be that the task of nursing me has become wearisome for you?
날 돌보는 일이 이젠 귀찮아진 건가?
Oh, no. No, no, my Lord Voldemort.
아닙니다 볼드모트 나으리
I only meant...
제 말은, 걜 빼고 하면 어떻겠냔 거죠
No! The boy is everything!
안돼! 걘 아주 중요해!
Lt cannot be done without him. And it will be done.
걔 없인 안돼
Exactly as I said.
내 지시대로만 일을 진행해!
- I will not disappoint you, my Lord. - Good.
실망 안 드리겠습니다
First, gather our old comrades.
그들을 부르자 이리와
Send them a sign.
신호를 보내게...
Nagini tells me the old Muggle caretaker...
내기니 말이 문 밖에서 웬 머글이
...is standing just outside the door.
엿듣고 있다는군
Step aside, Wormtail, so I can give our guest a proper greeting.
비켜봐, 웜테일 손님을 정중히 모셔야지
Avada Kedavra!
아바다 케다브라!
Harry.
해리
Harry!
해리!
Are you all right?
괜찮니?
Hermione. Bad dream.
헤르미온느 악몽을 꿨어
- When did you get here? - Just now. You?
언제 왔어?
Last night.
어젯밤에...
Wake up! Wake up, Ronald!
일어나, 빨리, 론!
Bloody hell.
젠장
Honestly, get dressed.
빨리 옷 입어
And don't go back to sleep.
다시 누울 생각 마!
Come on, Ron! Your mother says breakfast's ready!
일어나! 네 엄마가 아침 먹으래
- Ron, where are we actually going? - Don't know.
- 론, 어디 가는데? - 몰라
- Hey, Dad. Where are we going? - Haven't the foggiest.
아빠, 우리 어디 가요?
Arthur!
아서!
Lt's about time, son.
일찍 좀 오지
Sorry, Amos. Some of us had a bit of a sleepy start.
미안, 에이머스 애들이 늦잠을 자서...
This is Amos Diggory, everyone. Works with me at the Ministry.
내 마법부 동료 에이머스 디고리 씨다
And this strapping young lad must be Cedric, am I right?
이 늠름한 소년이 케드릭이군
This way.
이쪽입니다
Merlin's beard! You must be Harry Potter.
이런 영광이! 네가 해리 포터구나!
- Yes, sir. - Great, great pleasure.
네
Pleasure to meet you too, sir.
반갑습니다
Yes, it's just over there.
다 왔다 바로 저기야!
- Shall we? - Oh, yeah.
빨리 와
We don't want to be late.
이러다 늦을라
Come on. Nearly there now. Get yourself into a good position.
다 왔어 모두 여기 둘러서
Why are they all standing around that manky old boot?
저 더러운 장화로 뭐하게?
- That isn't just any manky old boot. - It's a Portkey.
- 그냥 장화 아냐 - 포트키야
Time to go!
준비됐지?
What's a Portkey?
포트키가 뭔데?
- Ready! After three. One, two... - Harry!
셋에 가는 거야 하나, 둘...
...three!
- 해리! - 셋!
Let go, kids!
손 떼!
- What?! - Let go!
손을 떼!
L'll bet that cleared your sinuses, eh?
졸음이 확 달아나지?
- Total shambles, as per usual. - Thanks.
- 좀 요란한 이동법이지 - 고마워
Go on, look at that!
얘들아, 저것 봐라
Well, kids, welcome to the Quidditch World Cup!
멋지지? 퀴디치 월드컵 경기장이야!
Stay together! Keep up, girls!
꼭 붙어다녀!
Look!
저기 봐!
Come on! Keep up, girls!
서둘러, 빨리 가자
Blimey!
깜짝이야!
Parting of the ways, I think, old chap.
여기서 헤어지세
- See you at the match. - See you.
시합 때 봐
- Cedric. - Ced, come on.
- 케드릭, 가자 - 내일 봐!
Home sweet home.
즐거운 나의 집!
What?
집?
- Excellent, excellent. - Ginny, look!
- 지니, 저것 봐! - 욕실도 멋진데?
Girls, choose a bunk and unpack.
침대 정하고 짐 풀어
Ron, get out of the kitchen. We're all hungry.
론, 뭘 먹니? 어서 나와!
I love magic.
마법은 멋진 거야
Get your Quidditch World Cup programs here!
월드컵 일정표요! 단돈 5시클!
Blimey, Dad. How far up are we?
더 가요? 좌석이 어디예요?
Well, put it this way:
내가 말해주지
Lf it rains...
비 오면 맨 먼저 비 맞을 자리야
Father and I are in the minister's box...
아빠랑 난 귀빈석이야
...by personal invitation of Cornelius Fudge himself.
마법부 장관이 초대해 줬거든
Don't boast, Draco.
관둬, 저런 애들한테 자랑해서 뭐하니?
Do enjoy yourself, won't you?
구경 실컷 해라, 해리
While you can.
할 수 있을 때...
Come on up. Take your seats. I told you these seats would be worth waiting for.
자리에들 앉아 힘들게 올라온 보람있지?
Come on!
야호!
Lt's the lrish! There's Troy!
아일랜드 팀 트로이다!
- And Mullet! - And Moran!
- 뮬레 - 로만이야!
Ireland! Ireland! Ireland!
아일랜드, 아일랜드!
- Here come the Bulgarians! - Yes!
불가리아 팀이다!
Who's that?
저건 누구지?
That, sis, is the best Seeker in the world.
세계 최고의 수색꾼이야!
Krum! Krum! Krum!
크룸, 크룸
Krum!
크룸!
Good evening!
안녕하십니까
As Minister for Magic...
마법부 장관입니다
...it gives me great pleasure...
올해로 422회째를 맞는
...to welcome each and every one of you...
퀴디치 월드컵 결승전에 오신
...to the final of the 422nd Quidditch World Cup!
여러분 모두를 진심으로 환영합니다!
Let the match...
이제 경기를...
...begin!
시작합니다!
There's no one like Krum.
크룸이 최고야
- Krum? - Dumb Krum?
- 크룸? - 그 멍청이?
He's like a bird, the way he rides the wind.
하늘을 나는 폼이 새 같애
- He's more than an athlete. - Dumb Krum.
그는 뭔가 달라
He's an artist.
예술가라구
- I think you're in love, Ron. - Shut up.
- 사귀지 그래? - 시끄러!
Viktor, I love you
- 사랑해요, 빅터 - 나의 빅터 크룸
When we're apart My heart beats only for you
자나깨나 그대 생각뿐
Sounds like the lrish have got their pride on.
아일랜드가 우승했나봐
Stop! Stop it!
그만들 해!
Lt's not the lrish.
아일랜드 팀이 아냐
We've gotta get out of here. Now!
여길 나가자, 빨리!
Get out, it's the Death Eaters!
'죽음을 먹는 자'들이다!
Get back to the Portkey, everybody, and stick together!
포트키로 가! 꼭 붙어다녀!
Fred, George! Ginny is your responsibility.
프레드, 조지 지니 잘 챙겨!
Harry!
해리!
- Keep up, you lot! - Harry!
뛰어!
Morsmordre!
모스모드레!
Harry!
해리!
- Where are you? - Harry!
어디 있니?
We've been looking for you for ages!
얼마나 찾았다구!
Thought we lost you, mate.
사고난줄 알았어
What is that?
저게 뭐지?
Stupefy!
스투페파이!
Stop!
안돼!
That's my son!
걘 내 아들이요!
- Ron, Harry, Hermione, you all right? - We came back for Harry.
론, 너희들 괜찮니?
Which of you conjured it?
누가 불러냈어?
- Crouch, you can't possi... - Do not lie!
- 크라우치, 무슨... - 말해!
You've been discovered at the scene of the crime.
- 범죄 현장에 있었잖아! - 범죄요?
- Crime? - Barty! They're just kids.
- 얘들은 애들이요! - 범죄라뇨?
Lt's the Dark Mark, Harry. It's his mark.
그건 어둠의 표식이었어
What, Voldemort?
볼드모트!
Those people tonight, in the masks, they're his too, aren't they?
그럼 가면 쓴 자들은...
Death Eaters.
'죽음을 먹는 자들'
- Follow me. - There was a man, before.
날 따라와
There!
저기서!
All of you, this way!
이리와, 이쪽이다!
A man, Harry?
어떤 남자라구?
Who?
누구?
I don't know.
모르겠어요
I didn't see his face.
얼굴은 못 봤어요
Anything from the trolley?
과자나 음료수요!
Anything from the trolley, dears?
과자나 음료수 사요
Packet of Drooble's...
껌 한 통과 감초 사탕 한 줄이요
On second thought, just the Drooble's.
그냥 껌만 주세요
- It's all right, l'll get it. Don't worry. - Just the Drooble's. Thanks.
- 내가 낼게 - 껌만 주세요
Two Pumpkin Pasties, please.
호박 파이 두개 주세요
Thank you.
고맙습니다
Anything sweet for you, dear?
학생은 뭐 줄까?
Oh, no, I'm not hungry. Thank you.
됐어요 배 안 고파요
Anything from the trolley?
과자나 음료수요!
This is horrible.
큰일이네
How can the Ministry not know who conjured it?
마법부는 왜 단서도 못 잡지?
Wasn't there any security or?
- 경비를 어떻게 한 거야? - 철통같이 했대
That's what worried them so much. Happened right under their noses.
그러니 더 문제지
It's hurting again, isn't it? Your scar.
또 아프니?
I'm fine.
괜찮아
You know Sirius will want to hear about this...
시리우스한테 알려야 되지 않아?
...what you saw at the World Cup and the dream.
월드컵 사건과 네 꿈 얘기...
Hedwig. There we go.
헤드위그 어서 전해줘
Clear the runway!
활주로를 비워!
Well, there's something you don't see every day.
평생 못 볼 구경거리네
Well, now we're all settled in and sorted, I'd like to make an announcement.
방 배정도 끝났으니 모두 잘 들으세요
This castle will not only be your home this year...
당분간 이 성엔 아주 특별한
...but home to some very special guests as well.
손님들이 묵게 됐습니다
You see, Hogwarts has been chosen...
올해 우리 호그와트가...
Tell them to wait. Tell them to wait. Wait.
잠깐 기다리라고 해
So Hogwarts has been chosen to host a legendary event:
우리가 전설적인 행사 트리위저드 시합을
The Triwizard Tournament.
주최하게 됐습니다
- For those of you who do not know... - Brilliant.
트리위저드는...
...the Triwizard Tournament brings together three schools...
3개 명문 학교가 벌이는
...for a series of magical contests.
마법 경연대회입니다
From each school, a single student is selected to compete.
각 학교에서 한 명씩 출전하죠
Now let me be clear.
출전자는 모든 걸
If chosen, you stand alone.
혼자 헤쳐가야 합니다
And trust me when I say...
웬만한 강심장 아니면 엄두도 못 낼 대회죠
But more of that later. For now, please join me in welcoming...
그 얘긴 차차 하고
...the lovely ladies of the Beauxbatons Academy of Magic...
보바통 아카데미의 아름다운 학생들과
...and their headmistress, Madame Maxime.
교장 선생님이신 마담 맥심!
Bloody hell.
끝내준다!
Blimey. That's one big woman.
우와, 무진장 크네
And now our friends from the north.
다음은 북유럽 학교
Please greet the proud sons of Durmstrang...
덤스트랭의 멋진 남학생들과
...and their high master, lgor Karkaroff.
이고르 카르카로프 교장!
Blimey, it's him!
내 우상이다!
Viktor Krum!
빅터 크룸
Albus.
알버스
Igor.
이고르
Professor Dumbly-dorr, my horses have traveled a long way.
제 말들이 긴 여행에 지쳤어요
- They will need attending to. - Don't worry, Madame Maxime.
- 휴식이 필요해요 - 염려 마시오
Our gamekeeper, Hagrid, is more than capable of seeing to them.
해그리드가 말을 잘 돌봐요
But you know, Monsieur Hagrid...
해그리드 씨, 우리말은
...they drink only single-malt whiskey.
고급 위스키만 마셔요
You idiot!
멍청이!
Your attention, please!
주목해 주세요!
I'd like to say a few words.
몇 마디만 하겠습니다
Eternal glory.
영원한 명예를
That is what awaits the student who wins the Triwizard Tournament.
트리위저드 우승자는 갖게 됩니다
But to do this, that student must survive three tasks.
그러려면 세 과제를 풀어야 합니다
Three extremely dangerous tasks.
굉장히 위험한 과제들이죠
- Wicked.
재밌겠네
For this reason, the Ministry has seen fit to impose a new rule.
그래서 마법부가 규정을 고쳤습니다
To explain all this...
자세한 내용은
...we have the head of the Department of International Magical Cooperation...
바티 크라우치 국제 마법 협력부장이
...Mr. Bartemius Crouch.
설명할 겁니다
Bloody hell. It's Mad-Eye Moody.
봐, 매드아이 무디야
- Alastor Moody? The Auror? - Auror?
앨러스터 무디? 오러?
Dark-wizard catcher. Half the cells in Azkaban are filled thanks to him.
사냥꾼! 어둠의 마법사 잡는...
He's supposed to be mad as a hatter, though, these days.
요즘 살짝 좀 돌았대
- My dear old friend, thanks for coming. - Stupid ceiling.
- 와줘서 고맙소 - 천장이 부실하네요
Thank you.
고맙습니다
What's that he's drinking, do you suppose?
뭘 마시는 거지?
I don't know, but I don't think it's pumpkin juice.
호박 주스는 아닌 것 같애
After due consideration...
저희 마법부에선
...the Ministry has concluded that, for their own safety...
참가자들의 안전을 위해
...no student under the age of 17...
17세 이상 학생들에게만
...shall be allowed to put forth their name for the Triwizard Tournament.
참가 신청서를 낼 자격을 주기로
- This decision is final. - That's rubbish!
- 결정했습니다 - 말도 안돼!
- Silence! - They're not too happy about that, then.
조용!
The Goblet of Fire.
불의 잔입니다
Anyone wishing to submit themselves to the tournament...
신청자들은 목요일 밤까지
...need only write their name upon a piece of parchment...
양피지에 이름을 적어
...and throw it in the flame before this hour on Thursday night.
불길 속에 던져 넣으세요
Do not do so lightly.
신중히 생각하세요
If chosen, there's no turning back.
선택되면 취소는 안됩니다
As from this moment, the Triwizard Tournament has begun.
이 순간부터 시합은 시작된 겁니다
Alastor Moody.
앨러스터 무디다
Ex-Auror...
한때 오러였고
...Ministry malcontent...
마법부 문제아였지
...and your new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
교장 선생의 부탁으로
I am here because Dumbledore asked me. End of story, goodbye, the end.
어둠의 마법 방어술 강의를 맡게 됐다
Any questions?
질문 있나?
When it comes to the Dark Arts...
난 방어술에 관한 한 실용적 접근법을 좋아한다
But first, which of you can tell me how many Unforgivable Curses there are?
용서받지 못할 저주가 몇 개인지 아는 사람?
- Three, sir. - And they are so named?
- 세 개입니다 - 왜 용서 못 받지?
Because they are unforgivable. The use of any one of them will...
금지 마법이니까요 그걸 쓰면...
Will earn you a one-way ticket to Azkaban, correct.
곧장 아즈카반 감옥행이지 맞았어!
The Ministry says you're too young to see what these curses do.
학생들에게 그 저주의 힘을 보여주는 건 불법이지만
I say different! You need to know what you're up against!
내 생각은 달라 알아야 싸우지!
You need to find another place to put your chewing gum...
왜 씹던 껌을
...besides the underside of your desk, Mr. Finnigan!
책상 밑에 붙이나 시무스 피니간?
No way. The old codger can see out the back of his head.
놀랍네 뒤통수에 눈 달렸나?
And hear across classrooms!
귀도 무진장 밝다!
So which curse shall we see first?
자...
- Weasley! - Yes?
- 위즐리? - 네?
Stand.
일어나!
Give us a curse.
아는 저주 있나?
Well, my dad did tell me about one.
아버지께 들은 게 하나 있습니다
The lmperius Curse.
- 임페리우스 저주요 - 그 저주, 네 부친도 잘 알지
Gave the Ministry quite a bit of grief a few years ago.
마법부의 피해가 컸거든
Perhaps this will show you why.
그 이유를 보여주지
Hello.
안녕
Lovely little beauty.
정말 예쁘지?
Engorgio.
엔고지오!
Imperio!
임페리오!
Don't worry. It's completely harmless.
걱정마 위험하지 않아
If she bites...
물론 물면
...she's lethal.
위험하지
What are you laughing at?
넌 왜 웃냐?
Get off!
저리가, 가!
Talented, isn't she?
또 뭘 시켜볼까? 창밖으로 점프시킬까?
Drown herself?
빠뜨려 죽일까?
Scores of witches and wizards have claimed...
죄를 지은 많은 마법사들이
...that they only did You-Know-Who's bidding...
'그 사람'의 이 저주에 걸려서
...under the influence of the lmperius Curse.
명령에 따랐다고 변명했다, 하지만
How do we sort out the liars?
그 말을 다 믿을 순 없지
Another, another.
딴 거 아는 사람?
Up, up. Come on.
너 일어나
Longbottom, is it?
롱바텀이지?
Up.
일어서
Professor Sprout tells me you have an aptitude for herbology.
스프라우트 교수 말로는 약초학을 잘한다고?
There's the...
두 번째 저주는... 크루시아투스 저주입니다
Correct, correct. Come, come.
정답, 정답! 나와봐
Particularly nasty.
고약한 저주지
The torture curse.
고통의 저주
Crucio!
크루시오!
Stop it! Can't you see it's bothering him? Stop it!
그만하세요 애가 괴로워하잖아요!
Perhaps you could give us the last Unforgivable Curse, Miss Granger.
마지막 저주는 네가 말해봐, 그레인저 양
No?
싫어?
Avada Kedavra!
아바다 케다브라!
The Killing Curse.
살인 저주다
Only one person is known to have survived it...
이걸 이겨낸 건 단 한 명뿐!
...and he's sitting in this room.
이 방안에 있지
Brilliant, isn't he?
대단하지 않냐?
Completely demented, of course, and terrifying to be in the same room with...
물론 정상은 아니지 왠지 섬뜩하고...
...but he's really been there, you know? He's looked evil in the eye.
하지만 경험 많고 실전에 강해
There's a reason those curses are unforgivable.
금지된 마법을 썼어
To perform them in a classroom... I mean, did you see Neville's face?
그것도 교실에서! 네빌의 표정 봤지?
Neville?
네빌?
Son?
이봐
You all right?
괜찮냐?
Come on. We'll have a cup of tea. I want to show you something.
따라와, 차 한잔 주마 보여줄 것도 있고...
Come on, Cedric. Put it in!
얼른, 케드릭!
Eternal glory. Be brilliant, wouldn't it?
영원한 명예! 멋지지 않냐?
Three years from now, when we're old enough to be chosen.
3년 후면 신청 자격 돼
Yeah, rather you than me.
넌 뽑힐 거다
Thank you, thank you.
- 어서 넣자 - 고맙다
- Well, lads, we've done it. - Cooked it up just this morning.
- 노화약을 만들었어 - 오늘 아침에!
It's not going to work.
소용없을걸?
- Oh, yeah? - And why is that, Granger?
- 그래? - 왜, 헤르미온느?
You see this? This is an Age Line.
이거 보여? 나이 제한선이야
Dumbledore drew it himself.
교장이 그어놨어
So?
그래서?
So a genius like Dumbledore couldn't possibly be fooled...
덤블도어 교장 같은 천재 마법사는
...by a dodge as pathetically dimwitted as an Aging Potion.
그런 엉터리 약에 안 속아
- But that's why it's so brilliant. - Because it's so pathetically dimwitted.
- 뭘 모르네 - 엉터리니까 속지
- Ready, Fred? - Ready, George.
- 준비됐냐? - 됐어
- Bottoms up.
쭉 마셔
Yeah!
좋았어!
Ready?
준비됐지?
- You said!
- 너 때문이야 - 뭐?
- Oh, right, you want a piece of me?! - L'll tear your ears off!
해보자 이거야?
Fight! Fight! Fight!
싸워라, 싸워라!
We're "old school," right?
- 우리 팍삭 늙었냐? - 그래, 몰랐냐?
Sit down. Please.
앉아!
Now the moment you've all been waiting for:
모두가 기다리던 챔피언 발표 시간입니다!
The Durmstrang champion is Viktor Krum.
덤스트랭 챔피언은 빅터 크룸!
The champion for Beauxbatons...
보바통 챔피언은... 플뢰르 델라쿠르!
The Hogwarts champion, Cedric Diggory!
호그와트 챔피언은 케드릭 디고리!
Excellent! We now have our three champions.
이제 세 챔피언이 정해졌습니다!
But in the end, only one will go down in history.
이중 역사에 남는 건 한 명뿐이죠
Only one will hoist this chalice of champions...
최후까지 남는 챔피언만이
...this vessel of victory...
차지할 수 있습니다
...the Triwizard Cup!
트리위저드 컵을!
Harry Potter.
해리 포터
Harry Potter?
해리 포터?
No. No.
안돼, 안돼...
Harry Potter!
해리 포터!
Go on, Harry.
나가봐
Harry, for goodness sake.
어서!
He's a cheat!
반칙 썼어!
He's not even 17 yet!
17살이 안됐어요!
- Harry. - I protest!
해리!
Did you put your name in the Goblet of Fire?
불의 잔에 이름 넣었니?
- No, sir. - Did you ask one of the older students...
아뇨
- You're absolutely sure? - Yes. Yes, sir.
- 확실한 거지? - 네!
- But of course he is lying. - The hell he is!
- 거짓말이에요 - 사실이오!
The Goblet of Fire is an exceptionally powerful magical object.
불의 잔을 속일 수 있는 건 강력한 '혼동 마법'뿐이요
Magic way beyond the talents of a fourth year.
4학년짜린 불가능해요
You seem to have given this a fair bit of thought, Mad-Eye.
어찌 그리 잘 아나 무디?
It was once my job to think as dark wizards do, Karkaroff...
어둠의 마법 연구하는 게 내 임무였잖나
Leave this to you, Barty.
당신이 결정해요
The rules are absolute.
마법의 계약상
The Goblet of Fire constitutes a binding magical contract.
불의 잔의 결정은 취소 못합니다
Mr. Potter has no choice.
선택권이 없어요
He is, as of tonight...
지금부터 포터 군도
...a Triwizard champion.
네 번째 챔피언입니다
This can't go on, Albus.
대책이 필요해요
First the Dark Mark. Now this?
어둠의 표식에 이어 이런 일까지...
What do you suggest, Minerva?
어쩌면 좋겠소?
Put an end to it.
시합을 취소해야죠!
Don't let Potter compete.
- 해리가 나가면 안돼요! - 취소는 안된다잖소
Well, the devil with Barty and his rules.
언제부터 마법부 지시에 그렇게 꼼짝 못했죠?
Headmaster, I, too, find it difficult to believe this mere coincidence.
제 생각에도 이건 우연 같진 않군요
However, if we are to truly discover the meaning of these events...
허나 사건의 진상을 파악하려면
...perhaps we should, for the time being...
당분간 모른 척 그냥 두고
...let them unfold.
지켜보는 게 어떨까요?
What...? Do nothing?
구경만 하자구요?
Offer him up as bait?
애를 미끼로?
Potter is a boy, not a piece of meat.
걘 실험용 쥐가 아녜요!
I agree. With Severus.
동의하오 스네이프 교수 말에...
Alastor, keep an eye on Harry, will you?
무디 해리를 지켜주시오
- I can do that. - Don't let him know, though.
- 그러죠 - 걔가 눈치 못 채게...
He must be anxious enough as it is...
안 그래도 시합껀으로
...knowing what lies ahead.
걱정이 태산일 텐데...
Then again, we all are.
우리도 그렇지만...
How did you do it?
어떻게 한 거야?
Never mind. Doesn't matter. Might've let your best friend know, though.
섭섭하다 단짝인 내게까지 숨겨?
- Let you know what? - You know bloody well what.
뭘 숨겨?
I didn't ask for this to happen, Ron.
이건 내가 원한 게 아냐
Okay?
알아?
- You're being stupid. - Yeah, that's me.
- 바보같이 왜 그래? - 나 바보야
Ron Weasley, Harry Potter's stupid friend.
해리 포터의 바보 친구 론 위즐리
I didn't put my name in that cup.
난 이름 안 넣었어
I don't want eternal glory. I just wanna be...
영원한 명예 따윈 관심도...
Look, I don't know what happened tonight, and I don't know why.
왜 그런 일이 생겼는지 나도 몰라
It just did.
진짜야
Okay?
알아?
Piss off.
웃기네
What a charismatic quartet.
환상의 4인조네
Hello.
안녕
I'm Rita Skeeter.
난 리타 스키터야
I write for the Daily Prophet.
예언자 일보의 기자...
But of course you know that, don't you? Lt's you we don't know.
나에 관해선 알지? 너희는 누굴까?
You're the juicy news.
특종 꺼리지!
What quirks lurk beneath those rosy cheeks?
요 통통한 뺨 속에 뭘 숨기고 있니?
What mysteries do the muscles mask?
이 표정 속에 무슨 비밀이 있지?
Does courage lie beneath those curls?
순진함을 가장한 배짱?
In short, what makes a champion tick?
챔피언의 본색은 뭘까?
"Me, Myself & l" want to know. Not to mention my rabid readers.
기자로서 궁금하군 독자들은 더 하겠지
So who's feeling up to sharing?
누가 먼저 입 열래?
Shall we start with the youngest? Lovely.
막내부터? 따라와!
This is cozy.
아늑하지?
It's a broom cupboard.
빗자루 창고예요
You should feel right at home, then.
집에 온 기분이겠네
Don't mind if I use a Quick-Quotes Quill, do you?
속기 깃펜 써도 되지?
No.
네
So tell me, Harry.
말해보렴, 해리
Here you sit, a mere boy of 12...
넌 겨우 12살밖에 안됐어
I'm 14. Sorry.
14살이에요
- About to compete against three students...
헌데 선배들과 붙게 됐지
...not only vastly more emotionally mature than yourself...
걔들은 너보다 훨씬 성숙하고
...but who have mastered spells that you wouldn't attempt...
네가 구경도 못해 본 온갖 마법을 터득했어
Concerned?
걱정 안되니?
I don't know. I haven't really thought about it.
깊게 생각 안 해봤어요
Just ignore the quill.
깃펜엔 신경 꺼
Then, of course, you're no ordinary boy of 12, are you?
넌 딴 12살짜리와 다르다?
- Fourteen. - Your story's legend.
- 14살이에요 - 네 전설 알아
Do you think it was the trauma of your past...
그 일의 충격 땜에
...that made you so keen to enter such a dangerous tournament?
이 위험한 시합에 나가고 싶었어?
No, I didn't enter.
- 전 신청 안했어요 - 변명 안 해도 돼
Everyone loves a rebel, Harry.
반칙해야 재밌지
Scratch that last.
방금 얘긴 지워
Speaking of your parents, were they alive, how do you think they'd feel?
부모님이 널 보면 마음이 어떠실까?
Proud? Or concerned...
내가 볼 때 넌
...that your attitude shows, at best, a pathological need for attention...
관심 끌려고 시합에 나가는 거야
...at worst, a psychotic death wish?
죽고 싶어 환장했거나!
Hey, my eyes aren't "glistening with the ghosts of my past."
잠깐만요! '과거 유령에 시달리는 눈빛'?
Harry, I couldn't risk sending Hedwig.
내 부엉이를 대신 보낸다
Since the World Cup, the Ministry's been intercepting more and more owls...
월드컵 이후 단속이 심해서 헤드위그는 위험해
We need to talk, Harry, face-to-face.
만나서 얘기 좀 하자
Meet me in the Gryffindor common room, 1:00 this Saturday night.
그리핀도르 휴게실에서 토요일 새벽 1시...
And make sure you're alone.
꼭 혼자 와
Sirius.
시리우스
P. S:
추신
The bird bites.
부엉이, 사납다
Sirius?
시리우스?
Harry Potter, age 12...
부정 참가자로 의심받는 12세의 해리 포터는
His eyes swimming with the ghosts of his past...
과거 유령에 사로잡혀 공포에 울먹이며...
Sirius. How...?
시리우스... 어떻게?
I don't have much time, so let me get straight to it.
본론만 얘기하마 해리
Did you or did you not put your name into the Goblet of Fire?
네가 불의 잔에 이름을 넣었니?
No!
아뇨!
I had to ask.
확인해본 거야 꿈 얘기 좀 해봐
- I don't know. - You didn't hear a name?
몰라요
No.
네
Voldemort was giving him a job to do. Something important.
볼드모트가 그에게 임무를 맡겼어요
And what was that?
무슨 임무?
He wanted...
그의 목적은...
me
저였어요
I don't know why. But he was gonna use this man to get to me.
그 남잘 이용 제게 접근하려는 거죠
But, I mean, it was only a dream, right?
하지만 꿈일 뿐이에요
Yes.
그래
It's just a dream.
그렇긴 해도
The Death Eaters at the World Cup, your name rising from that goblet...
월드컵 사건이나 불의 잔이 널 호명한 건
...these are not just coincidences. Hogwarts isn't safe anymore.
우연이 아냐 이젠 여기도 위험해
What are you saying?
왜죠?
I'm saying the devils are inside the walls. Igor Karkaroff?
이고르 카르카로프도 '죽음을 먹는 자'였어
He was a Death Eater. And no one, no one stops being a Death Eater.
'죽음을 먹는 자'는 그 본색이 변치 않아
Then there's Barty Crouch. Heart of stone. Sent his own son to Azkaban.
바티 크라우치도 무서운 자야
You think one of them put my name in the goblet?
그중 하나가 제 이름을...?
I haven't a clue who put your name in that goblet...
그게 누군진 모르지만
...but whoever did is no friend to you. People die in this tournament.
시합에 내보내서 널 해치려는 게 분명해
- I'm not ready for this, Sirius. - You don't have a choice.
- 전 겁나요 - 출전을 피할 순 없어
- Someone's coming. - Keep your friends close, Harry.
- 누가 와요 - 혼자 다니지 마!
Who were you talking to?
누구랑 말했니?
- What? Who says I was talking to anyone? - I heard voices.
- 얘길 하다니, 누가? - 말소릴 들었어
Maybe you're imagining things. Wouldn't be the first time.
환청을 들었구나 너 잘 그러잖아
You're probably just practicing for your next interview, I expect.
기자 회견 연습 중이셨나보지?
Amazing.
대단하다
- Amazing! - Neville. You're doing it again.
- 대단해! - 네빌, 뭘 또 중얼대?
Right, sorry.
미안해
"Magical Water Plants of the Highland Lochs"?
'호수에 사는 마법의 식물들'?
Moody gave it to me. That day we had tea.
차 마시던 날 무디 교수가 줬어
It's already been through enough people.
몇 입을 거치는 거야? 네가 직접 말해!
Ron, this is your problem, not mine.
너 땜에 돌겠다
What do you want me to say again?
뭐라고 전하라구?
Ronald would like me to tell you that Seamus told him...
패르바티가 딘에게 한 얘길 시무스를 통해
...that Dean was told by Parvati that Hagrid's looking for you.
론이 들었는데 해그리드가 널 찾는대
Is that right? Well, you...
그래?
What?
뭐라구?
Dean was told by Parvati that...
패르바티가 딘에게 한 얘길...
Please don't ask me to say it again.
이젠 반복 못하겠다 해그리드에게 가봐
- Well, you can tell Ronald... - I'm not an owl!
- 론한테 전해... - 나 부엉이 아냐!
Did you bring your father's cloak, like I asked you?
투명 망토는 가져왔지?
Yeah, I brought the cloak. Hagrid, where are we going?
네 어디 가는 거예요?
You'll see soon enough.
곧 알게 돼
Now pay attention, this is important.
눈 크게 뜨고 따라와
What's with the flower?
꽃은 왜 달았죠?
Hagrid, have you combed your hair?
머리도 빗었어요?
As a matter of fact, I have.
빗으면 안되냐?
You might like to try the same thing now and again.
남자도 가끔 가꿔줘야 돼
Hagrid?
해그리드?
The cloak! Put the cloak on!
망토, 빨리 망토 써!
- Bonsoir, Olympe. - Oh, Hagrid.
봉주르, 마담
I thought perhaps you weren't coming. I thought perhaps...
안 오시는 줄 알았어요 그새 날...
...you had forgotten me.
잊은 줄 알았어요
Couldn't forget you, Olympe.
어떻게 당신을 잊겠소
What is it you wanted to show me?
보여주겠다는 게 뭐죠?
When we spoke earlier, you sounded so...
그날 얘기할 때 목소리가
...exhilarated.
흥분되셨던데...
You'll be glad you came. Trust me.
보면 잘 왔다 싶을 거요
Can we get closer?
가까이 가봐도 돼요?
Dragons?
용이잖아요!
That's the first task?
저게 첫 번째 과제군요! 말도 안돼!
These are seriously misunderstood creatures.
용은 생각 보단 온순해
Oh, crikey!
피해!
Although, I have to admit, that Horntail is a right nasty piece of work.
물론 혼테일이란 놈은 약간 포악하지
Poor Ron nearly fainted just seeing him, you know.
론은 저걸 보고 졸도했어
- Ron was here? - Oh, sure.
론도 봤어요?
Didn't Ron tell you that?
말 안 하든?
No, he didn't.
안했어요
He didn't tell me a thing.
한 마디도...
- You cheat, Potter. - You stink, Potter.
- 포터 - 넌 야비해
- Good luck, Potter. - Potter stinks!
포터는 야비해!
- Cedric rules. - Thanks.
케드릭이 이겨
Like the badge?
뱃지 멋지지?
Excuse me.
비켜줘
Harry.
해리
Hey! Read the badge, Potter!
- 뱃지 봤냐? - 얘기 좀 해
- All right. - You stink, Potter!
좋아
- Potter, you stink! - Harry Potter smells!
사깃꾼!
Dragons. That's the first task.
첫 과제가 용이야 한 마리씩 배당되나봐
Are you serious?
진짜야?
And Fleur and Krum, do they...?
- 딴 애들도 알아? - 응
- Read the badges, Potter! - Hey, listen. About the badges.
뱃지, 미안해 떼라고 해도...
It's not like I try to blow things up, exactly.
왜 자꾸 폭발하는 걸까?
It just happens a fair bit.
뭐가 잘못됐나?
You have to admit, though, fire's pretty fascinating.
그래도 불꽃은 멋지지?
You're a right foul git, you know that?
넌 진짜 멍청이야!
- You think so? - I know so.
- 그래? - 그래!
Anything else?
또 할 말 있냐?
- Yeah. Stay away from me. - Fine.
응, 내 곁에 얼씬마
- There's Potter. Cheat. - Why so tense, Potter?
포터 아냐?
My father and I have a bet, you see.
울 아빠랑 내기했어
I don't think you're gonna last 10 minutes in this tournament.
난 네가 10분도 못 버틴다고 했지
He disagrees. He thinks you won't last five.
아빤 5분도 못 버틸 거래
I don't give a damn what your father thinks, Malfoy.
두 사람 생각 따위 관심 없어!
He's vile and cruel. And you're just pathetic.
네 아빤 냉혈한이고 넌 한심하니까!
- Pathetic? - Oh, no, you don't, sonny!
한심해?
L'll teach you to curse someone when their back is turned!
등 뒤에서 마법을 걸어?
You stinking, cowardly, scummy...
이 비겁하고 치사하고 못된 놈
- Professor Moody! ...back-shooting...
무디 교수님 지금 뭐해요?
- Is that a...? Ls that a student? - Technically, it's a ferret.
그거, 학생 아녜요?
Stand still! Stand still!
가만히 있어봐!
- My father will hear about this! - Is that a threat?
아빠한테 이를 거야!
Professor!
교수님!
I could tell you stories about your father that would curl even your greasy hair!
네 아버지가 어떤 작자인지 말해줘?
- Alastor! Alastor. - It doesn't end here!
두고 보자!
Surely Dumbledore told you that.
교장이 말했을 텐데요?
- He might've mentioned it. - Well, you will do well to remember it.
들은 것 같네요
Away!
가거라!
You. Come with me.
너, 따라와!
That's a Foe-Glass.
적 탐지기야
Lets me keep an eye on my enemies.
적의 동향을 알려주지
If I can see the whites of their eyes, they're standing right behind me.
가까이 적이 있을 땐 영상이 또렷해져!
Wouldn't even bother telling you what's in there.
뭔 소린지 묻지마 말해도 못 믿을 테니...
Now...
그래...
...what are you going to do about your dragon?
용과 어떻게 싸울 거냐?
Well, you know, I just thought I'd...
글쎄요... 아직은 잘...
Sit.
앉아
Listen to me, Potter.
잘 들어, 포터
Your pal Diggory?
케드릭은
By your age, he could turn a whistle into a watch and have it sing you the time.
네 나이 때 호루라기를 시계로 변신시켰어
Miss Delacour?
플뢰르는
She's as much a fairy princess as I am.
여자지만 나만큼 터프하지
As for Krum, his head may be filled with sawdust...
크룸은 좀 단순 무식하지만
...but Karkaroff's is not.
카르카로프는 달라
They'll have a strategy.
전략이 탄탄해
And you can bet that it will play to Krum's strengths.
크룸에게 큰 힘이 돼 줄 거야
Come on, Potter.
말해보렴
What are your strengths?
네 전략은 뭐냐?
I don't know.
모르겠어요
Well, I can fly. I mean, I'm a fair flyer. But I...
하늘을 나는 건 잘하지만...
- Better than fair, the way I heard it. - But I'm not allowed a broom.
- 알아, 소문 들었다 - 빗자루를 못 쓴대요
You're allowed a wand.
지팡이 사용은 허용돼
Bets! Place your bets!
내기들 걸어
Bets taken! Bets taken here!
돈 놓고 돈 먹기!
Step up, folks! Who fancies a flutter in today's bloodbath?
오늘 시합에 내기 걸 사람!
Smart money's on Krum to survive! Any bets?
크룸한테 걸면 확률 100%!
Yes, sir?
누구 걸 거야?
Ten-to-1 for Fleur. There you go. Thank you very much.
플뢰르한테 10대 1!
Your attention, please.
모두 주목하세요!
This is a great day for all of us.
드디어 시합 날입니다
Each of the three tasks involves very considerable danger.
세 가지 과제엔 큰 위험이 따릅니다
Please keep your seats at all times.
절대 일어나선 안돼요
- Harry? Ls that you? - Yeah.
해리? 너 맞지?
- How are you feeling? Okay? ...the greatest of luck.
기분 어때? 괜찮니?
The key is to concentrate. After that, you just have to...
우선 정신을 집중해 그리고...
Battle a dragon.
용과 싸워야지
Young love.
젊은 연인들!
How...
정말...
...stirring.
충격이네
If everything goes unfortunately today...
시합 결과가 안 좋게 끝나면
...you two may even make the front page.
둘이 1면에 나겠는데?
You have no business here.
외부인 출입금지예요
This tent is for champions...
시합 챔피언과
...and friends.
친구들 외엔!
No matter. We've got what we wanted.
갈 거야
Good day, champions. Gather round, please.
잘 잤니, 챔피언들? 모여봐
Now, you've waited, you've wondered, and at last the moment has arrived.
두려움 속에 고대하던 날이 밝았다
A moment only four of you can fully appreciate.
오늘의 주인공은 너희야
What are you doing here, Miss Granger?
넌 여기 웬일이니?
Sorry, l'll just go.
나가던 참입니다
Barty, the bag.
주머니 가져와요
Champions, in a circle around me.
내 주위로 빙 둘러서
Miss Delacour, over here. Mr. Krum.
플뢰르 양은 여기...
And, Potter, Mr. Potter, over here. That's right. Now...
포터 군은 여기 서
...Miss Delacour, if you will.
플뢰르 양, 하나 뽑아
The Welsh Green.
웨일스 그린!
Mr. Krum.
크룸 군
The Chinese Fireball.
중국 파이어볼
The Swedish Short-Snout.
스웨덴 쇼트 스나우트
- Which leaves... - The Horntail.
그럼 남은 건...
- What's that, boy? - Nothing.
- 뭐? - 아녜요
The Hungarian Horntail.
헝가리 혼테일이다
These represent four very real dragons...
각자 뽑은 건 진짜 용의 축소판이야
...each of which has been given a golden egg to protect.
용들은 황금알을 지키고 있다
Your objective is simple:
임무는 간단하다 그 알을 쟁취하는 것!
This you must do, for each egg contains a clue...
알속에 감춰진 단서가 없인
...without which you cannot hope to proceed to the next task.
다음 과제로 옮겨갈 수 없어
Any questions?
질문 있나?
Very well. Good luck, champions.
좋아
Diggory! Diggory! Diggory!
케드릭, 케드릭, 케드릭
Three of our champions have now faced their dragons...
세명 다 용을 물리쳤으므로
...and so each one of them will proceed to the next task.
2단계 진출 자격을 얻었습니다
And now our fourth and final contestant.
이제 마지막 네 번째 도전자입니다
Your wand, Harry! Your wand!
지팡이를 써 요술 지팡이!
Accio Firebolt!
아씨오 파이어볼트!
- Yeah! - Yes!
좋았어!
- Yeah! - Yeah! Well done, dragon!
그래, 잘했어, 용아!
Yes! Yes!
좋아, 잘했어!
- Yes, Harry! - Knew you wouldn't die, Harry. Lose a leg.
- 안 죽을 줄 알았어 - 부상 정도 예상했지
Shush!
조용!
Go on, Harry. What's the clue?
어서 열어봐 단서가 뭘까?
- Who wants me to open it? - Yes!
다들 궁금하지?
- Do you want me to open it?
열어볼까?
What the bloody hell was that?
귀청 떨어지겠네!
All right, everyone! Go back to your knitting.
우린 그만 사라져주자
This is gonna be uncomfortable enough without all you nosy sods listening in.
둘이서 조용히 해결 보게...
I reckon you have to be barking mad to put your own name in the Goblet of Fire.
하긴 제 정신이면 이름을 넣을 리 없지
Caught on, have you? Took you long enough.
이제 깨달았냐? 둔하긴...
I wasn't the only one who thought you'd done it.
나만 오해한 게 아냐
Everyone was saying it behind your back.
다들 뒤에서 널 욕했어
Brilliant. That makes me feel loads better.
고맙다
- Least I warned you about the dragons. - Hagrid warned me about the dragons.
- 난 용 얘긴 해줬어 - 해그리드가 해줬지
No, no, no, I did.
내가 해준 거야
No, don't you remember? I told Hermione to tell you...
패르바티와 딘 시무스를 통해
...that Seamus told me that Parvati told Dean that Hagrid was looking for you.
해그리드가 찾는다고 전한 거
Seamus never actually told me anything, so it was really me all along.
실은 내가 한 얘기야 걔들은 핑계고...
I thought we'd be all right, you know...
네가 그래도 알아듣고
...after you'd figured that out.
화 풀 줄 알았어
Who...? Who could possibly figure that out?
그걸 어떻게 알아듣냐?
That's completely mental.
넌 참 엉뚱해
Yeah. Isn't it?
그래, 맞아 난 가끔 진짜 웃겨
Boys.
못 말려
- Hi, Harry.
안녕, 해리
Cho, Harry's looking at you.
초, 해리가 널 본다
Look at this!
이것 봐!
I can't believe it! She's done it again.
엉터리 기사를 또 썼어
"Miss Granger, a plain but ambitious girl...
'평범한 용모의 그레인저 양은 유명한 마법사만 꼬신다'
Her latest prey, sources report...
'현재 그녀의 표적은'
...is none other than the Bulgarian bonbon, Viktor Krum.
'불가리아 퀴디치 스타 빅터 크룸이다'
No word yet on how Harry Potter's taking this latest emotional blow."
'실연당한 포터의 반응은 알려진 바 없다'
Parcel for you, Mr. Weasley.
소포 왔어요, 형
Thank you, Nigel.
고맙다, 나이젤
Not now, Nigel. Later.
나중에 받아줄게
Go on.
가봐
I told him I'd get him Harry's autograph.
해리 사인 받아준댔거든
Oh, look, Mum's sent me something.
엄마가 뭘 보냈네
Mum sent me a dress.
드레스잖아
Well, it does match your eyes. Is there a bonnet?
너랑 어울린다 모자도 있냐?
Nose down, Harry.
내려놔, 해리
- Ginny, these must be for you. - I'm not wearing that, it's ghastly.
지니, 네 껀가봐
What are you on about?
왜 웃어?
They're not for Ginny.
지니 옷 아냐
They're for you.
네 옷이야
- Dress robes. - Dress robes? For what?
- 연회복이라구 - 연회복은 뭐하게?
The Yule Ball...
크리스마스 무도회는
...has been a tradition of the Triwizard Tournament...
트리위저드 시합이 생긴 이후로
...since its inception.
계속돼 온 전통입니다
On Christmas Eve night, we and our guests...
이브 날 주최측과 손님들이
...gather in the Great Hall...
연회장에서 품위있게 파티를 즐기는 거죠
As representatives of the host school...
주최측 학생들로서
...I expect each and every one of you to put your best foot forward.
여러분 모두 춤을 출 줄 알아야 합니다
And I mean this literally, because...
그날의 무도회에서
...the Yule Ball is, first and foremost...
그 무엇보다도 중요한 건 바로
...a dance.
춤입니다!
Silence!
조용!
The house of Godric Gryffindor has commanded the respect...
그리핀도르는 마법사 세계에서
...of the wizard world for nearly 10 centuries.
근 천년간 존경 받아왔어요
I will not have you, in the course of a single evening, besmirching that name...
하룻밤 동안의 품위없는 언행으로
...by behaving like a babbling, bumbling band of baboons.
그 명성에 먹칠 않게 명심, 명심하세요
Try saying that five times fast, huh?
저 말, 빨리 따라해봐
Now, to dance...
춤은 온몸으로 호흡하는 겁니다
Inside every girl, a secret swan slumbers...
모든 소녀들 몸속엔 백조가
...longing to burst forth and take flight.
날개를 접고 숨어 있답니다
Something's about to burst out of Eloise Midgen, but I don't think it's a swan.
엘로이즈 몸속엔 거위가 숨어 있을걸?
Inside every boy, a lordly lion prepared to prance.
소년들 몸속엔 사자가 숨어 있죠
- Mr. Weasley. - Yes?
위즐리 군!
Will you join me, please?
같이 한곡 출까요?
Now, place your right hand on my waist.
오른손을 내 허리에 대요
- Where? - My waist.
어디요?
And extend your arm.
팔을 쭉 뻗고...
Mr. Filch, if you please.
필치 씨, 음악!
One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋
One, two, three. One, two, three.
하나, 둘, 셋...
Never gonna let him forget this, are you?
이제 평생 놀릴 꺼리 생겼네?
- Never.
당근이지
Everybody come together. Boys, on your feet!
다 나와요 남학생들 일어나요!
Why do they have to travel in packs?
왜 다들 몰려다니지?
How are you supposed to get one on their own to ask them?
말을 못 걸겠잖아
Blimey, Harry. You've slayed dragons. If you can't get a date, who can?
용을 죽인 네가 여자애들이 겁나?
I think I'd take the dragon right now.
용보다 훨씬 겁나
I take after my mum.
난 엄말 닮았대요
Though I didn't know her very well. She left when I was about 3.
세살 때 돌아가셔서 기억이 없소
No, not the maternal sort, her.
아버진 상심이 컸죠
Broke me dad's heart, though. He was a tiny little fella, my dad.
울 아버진 체격이 작았소
I could pick him up at the age of 6 with one hand and put him up on the dresser.
6살 때 내가 한 손으로 들어올렸죠
He laughed so hard at that.
그럼, 막 웃으셨는데...
And then he died just when I started school, so...
학교 다닐 때 돌아가셨소
So I sort of had to make me own way, as it were.
그래서 난 혼자 컸죠
But enough of me. What about you?
당신 얘기 좀 해봐요
This is mad. At this rate, we'll be the only ones in our year without dates.
이러다간
Well, us and Neville.
우리랑 네빌...
Yeah, but, then again, he can take himself.
쟨 혼자 잘 추잖아
It might interest you to know that Neville's already got someone.
네빌도 파트너 구했대
Now I'm really depressed.
진짜 우울하네
"Get a move on or all the good ones will have gone."
'동작 굼뜨면 퀸카 다 뺏긴다'
Who you going with, then?
형들은 구했어?
- Oi, Angelina? - What?
어이, 안젤리나
Do you wanna go to the ball with me?
나하고 무도회에 같이 갈래?
To the ball?
무도회에?
Yeah, all right.
좋아
Oi, Hermione.
어이, 헤르미온느
You're a girl.
너도 여자지?
Very well spotted.
- 어떻게 알았어? - 같이 갈래?
Come on. It's one thing for a bloke to show up alone.
남잔 혼자 가도 되지만
For a girl, it's just sad.
여잔 개망신이야
I won't be going alone, because, believe it or not, someone's asked me!
나 혼자 안 가! 데이트 신청 받았어
And I said yes!
응낙했어!
Bloody hell.
젠장
She's lying, right?
뻥이겠지?
Lf you say so.
글쎄다
Look, we've just gotta grit our teeth and do it.
우리도 용기 내서 구해보자
Tonight, when we get back to the common room, we'll both have partners. Agreed?
오늘밤도 휴게실에서 기죽을 순 없어, 오케이?
Agreed.
오케이!
- Cho! - Harry!
- 초 - 해리!
Watch yourself on the stairs. It's a bit icy at the top.
계단 조심해 얼음이 있어
Okay, thanks.
고마워
Cho?
초?
Yes?
응?
Well, I just wondered if you...
혹시 나랑...
I wondered if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with me.
무도회에 같이 안 갈래?
Sorry, I didn't catch that.
미안해 잘 못 들었어
I was just wondering if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with me.
나랑 무도회에 같이 안 가겠냐구
Harry...
미안해
...l'm sorry, but someone's already asked me.
같이 가자는 애가 있어서...
Well, I've said l'll go with him.
가겠다고 벌써 대답했어
Okay. Yeah. Great.
그랬구나 그래, 알았어
Fine. No problem.
괜찮아
Harry?
해리?
I really am...
미안해
sorry
정말로...
lt's all right, Ron.
괜찮아, 오빠
It's okay, Ron. It's all right. It doesn't matter.
그럴 수도 있지 잊어버려
What happened to you?
왜 그래?
He just asked Fleur Delacour out.
- 플뢰르한테 데이트 신청했어 - 뭐?
No, of course.
거절했지?
- She said yes? - Don't be silly.
- 그럼, 좋대? - 얘길 들어봐
There she was, walking by. You know how I like it when they walk.
그녀가 걸어가는데 그 모습이 예뻐서...
I couldn't help it. It just sort of slipped out.
나도 모르게...
Actually, he sort of screamed at her. It was a bit frightening.
고함을 질렀지 깜짝 놀라게...
- And what did you do then? - What else? I ran for it.
- 그리곤 어쨌어? - 어쩌긴, 튀었지
I'm not cut out for this, Harry. I don't know what got into me.
그냥 다 포기할래 난 머저리야
- Hi, Harry.
안녕, 해리
I always liked looking at them from behind.
여자 앞에선 늘 쫄기만 해
She's never gonna forgive me, ever.
걘 날 용서 안 할 거야
Hey!
잠깐만!
Bloody hell.
젠장
What are those? What are those?
그 옷, 뭐야? 너 입은 거!
- My dress robes. - Well, they're all right!
연회복이야
No lace. No dodgy little collar.
알록달록 레이스도 없고...
Well, I expect yours are more traditional.
네 옷은 고풍스럽...
Traditional?! They're ancient! I look like my Great Aunt Tessie!
고풍? 고물 같지! 나 꼭 할머니 같잖냐?
I smell like my Great Aunt Tessie.
옷에서 할머니 냄새 나
Murder me, Harry.
살고 싶지 않다
Leave it alone!
그만 만져
Poor kid. I bet she's alone in her room, crying her eyes out.
가엾은 것... 지금 혼자 울고 있겠지?
- Who? - Hermione, of course.
누구?
Come on, Harry, why do you think she wouldn't tell us who she's coming with?
파트너 있으면 왜 말 안했겠냐?
Because we'd take the mickey out of her if she did.
놀릴까봐 그랬겠지
Nobody asked her. Would've taken her myself if she wasn't so bloody proud.
신청자가 없었던 거야 나라도 데리고 올걸...
- Hello, boys.
얘들아, 안녕
Don't you look...
너 참...
...dashing.
멋지다
There you are, Potter. Are you and Miss Patil ready?
해리, 파트너하고 준비됐지?
- Ready, professor? - To dance.
준비요?
- Surely I told you that. - No.
내가 말 안했어?
Well, now you know.
이젠 말했으니 준비해
As for you, Mr. Weasley, you may proceed into the Great Hall with Miss Patil.
론, 넌 파드마와 연회장으로 들어가
- Oh, there you are. - Come on, then.
- 왔구나! - 가자
Come along this way.
이쪽으로 와
Oh, come on.
빨리 와
- Hi. - Now, I need you all to line up...
들어가면 한 쌍씩 줄 서
She looks beautiful!
정말 예쁘다
Yeah, she does.
그렇지?
Is that Hermione Granger? With Viktor Krum?
크룸 옆에 있는 애 헤르미온느지?
No. Absolutely not.
아냐, 그럴 리가 없어
Hi!
안녕!
Harry, take my waist.
해리, 내 허리를 잡아
- What? - Now!
- 뭐? - 빨리!
Are you ready?
준비됐지?
Move your body like a hairy troll
털보 트롤처럼 춤을 춰봐
Learning to rock and roll
로큰롤 음악에 맞춰
Spin around like a crazy elf
미친 요정처럼 흔들어봐
Dancing by himself
신나게 춤을 춰봐
Boogie down like a unicorn
유니콘처럼 터프하게 밤이 새도록 놀아봐
Put your hands up in the air
두 손을 높이 쳐들고
Like an ogre who just don't care
신나게 몸을 흔들어봐
Can you dance like a Hippogriff?
히포그리프처럼 신나게!
Ruddy pumpkinhead, isn't he?
물 만난 고기 같군
I don't think it was the books that had him going to the library.
도서관 들락댈 때 수상했어
May I have your arm?
손 주실까요?
Arm. Leg. I'm yours.
손? 발이라도 줄게요
Hot, isn't it?
무척 덥지?
Viktor's gone to go and get drinks. Would you care to join us?
음료수 가지러 갔어 같이 마실래?
No, we'd not care to join you and Viktor.
아니, 빅터랑 상대하기 싫어
What's got your wand in a knot?
왜 또 심통 부려?
He's a Durmstrang. You're fraternizing with the enemy.
걘 덤스트랭이야
The enemy? Who was it wanting his autograph?
적? 언젠 걔한테 사인해 달라더니!
Besides, the whole point of the tournament...
트리위저드 시합의 목적은
...is international magical cooperation...
마법 세계의 친선 도모야!
...to make friends.
화합하는 거!
I think he's got a bit more than friendship on his mind.
걔 목적은 친선이 아닐걸?
Are you going to ask me to dance or not?
춤 출 거야, 말 거야?
No.
안 춰
- He's using you. - How dare you?!
- 넌 이용당하고 있어 - 말조심해! 내가 바보니?
- What?! What? That's what you think? - Yeah, that's what I think.
뭐? 그래서 아니꼽니?
You know the solution then, don't you?
그럼 해결책이 있네
- Go on. - Next time there's a ball...
뭔데?
And not as a last resort.
괜히 뒷북치지 말고!
Well, that's... I mean, that's just completely off the point.
얘가 또 황당한 소리하네
Harry.
해리
Where have you been?
어디 갔었니?
Never mind! Off to bed, both of you.
됐어 가서 잠이나 자!
- They get scary when they get older. - Ron, you spoiled everything!
- 쟨 갈수록 이상해져 - 너 때문에 기분 잡쳤어!
What's this about?
왜 그래?
No, don't let
난 사랑의
This magic die
마법에 빠졌다오
The answer's there
내 마음 받아주오
Let me see it again.
다시 보여다오
Yes, the time is close now.
그래 때가 가까이 왔다
Harry, at last!
해리, 왔구나!
Step aside, Wormtail, so I can give our guest a proper greeting.
비켜봐, 웜테일 손님을 정중히 모셔야지
You all right, Harry?
괜찮니, 해리?
I just got in.
방금 왔어
Me.
나야
Harry, you told me you'd figured the egg out weeks ago.
황금알의 단서를 풀었다며?
- The task is two days from now. - Really? I had no idea.
이틀 후에 시합이야
I suppose Viktor's already figured it out.
크룸도 단서 풀었지?
Wouldn't know. We don't actually talk about the tournament.
몰라, 시합 얘긴 안 해
Actually, we don't really talk at all. Viktor's more of a physical being.
사실 대화를 잘 안 해 걘 운동만 잘하나봐
I just mean he's not particularly loquacious.
내 얘긴, 통 말이 없다구
Mostly, he watches me study.
나 책 읽는 걸 지켜만 봐
It's a bit annoying, actually.
솔직히 부담돼
You are trying to figure this egg out, aren't you?
너 아직 단서 못 풀었지?
What's that supposed to mean?
그건 왜 물어?
Lt just means these tasks are designed to test you...
불안해서 그래 시합과제가 널 겨냥한 것 같애
And...
네가 걱정돼
You got by the dragons mostly on nerve.
용은 용기로 물리쳤지만 이번엔 그걸로 부족해
Hey, Potter!
포터!
- Potter! - Cedric.
- 포터! - 케드릭 형!
How...? How are you?
컨디션 어때?
Spectacular.
아주 좋아
I realize I never really thanked you properly for tipping me off about those dragons.
용 얘기 귀띔해준 거 고마웠어
Forget it. I'm sure you would've done the same for me.
형이라도 그랬을 거야
Exactly.
당연하지!
You know the Prefects' bathroom on the fifth floor?
5층의 반장 욕실 알지?
Lt's not a bad place for a bath.
거기 가서 목욕 좀 해
Just take your egg...
황금 알을 보며
...and mull things over in the hot water.
욕조에서 연구 좀 해봐
I must be out of my mind.
나도 참 한심하군
I'm definitely out of my mind.
기대한 게 바보지
I'd try putting it in the water if I were you.
나라면 알을 물속에 넣을 거야
Myrtle!
머틀!
Hello, Harry.
안녕, 해리
Long time no see.
너 진짜 오랜만이다
I was circling a blocked drain the other day...
며칠 전에 배수구 쪽을 맴돌다
...and could swear I saw a bit of Polyjuice Potion.
'1시간 변신 폴리 주스'를 발견했어
Not being a bad boy again, are you, Harry?
또 나쁜 짓 꾸미는 거 아냐?
Polyjuice Potion?
폴리 주스?
Kicked the habit. Myrtle, did you say, "Try putting it in the water"?
이젠 안 만들어 이 알을 물에 넣으라구?
That's what he did.
걔도 그랬거든
The other boy...
네 선배 말야
...the handsome one...
잘생긴 남자애
...Cedric.
케드릭
Well, go on. Open it.
뭐해? 어서 열어봐
Come seek us Where our voices sound
우리의 음성이 들리는 곳으로 와요
We cannot sing Above the ground
우린 땅에선 노래를 못 불러요
An hour long you'll have to look
한시간 안에 그대는 찾아야 해요
To recover what we took
우리가 그대에게서 빼앗은 걸...
Myrtle...
머틀
...there aren't merpeople in the Black Lake, are there?
검은 호수에 인어가 살지?
Very good.
역시 빠르네
It took Cedric ages to riddle it out.
케드릭은 한참 걸려서 알아냈어
Almost all the bubbles were gone.
욕조의 거품이 다 꺼질 때쯤...
Harry, tell me again.
다시 말해봐
"Come seek us where our voices sound."
'우리 음성이 들리는 곳으로 와요'
The Black Lake, that's obvious.
검은 호수가 분명해
"An hour long you'll have to look."
'한시간 안에 찾아야 해요'
Again, obvious. Though, admittedly, potentially problematic.
검은 호수 맞아 문제가 좀 있겠다
"Potentially problematic"?
문제가 '좀' 있겠다?
When's the last time you held your breath underwater for an hour, Hermione?
너, 물속에서 1시간 버텨봤어?
Look, Harry, we can do this. The three of us can figure it out.
염려마
Hate to break up the skull session.
방해해서 미안한데 맥고나걸 교수께 가봐
Not you, Potter, just Weasley and Granger.
해리 말고 너희 둘만!
But, sir, the second task is only hours away, and...
몇 시간 후면 시합이에요
Exactly. Presumably Potter is well prepared by now...
해리는 준비가 됐을 게다 이제 좀 자야지
Go. Now!
가, 어서!
Longbottom!
롱바텀!
Why don't you help Potter put his books back.
책 정리하는 거 도와줘
You know, if you're interested in plants...
너, 식물에 관심 있으면
...you'd be better off with Goshawk's Guide to Herbology.
'약초학 입문'을 읽어봐
Do you know there's a wizard in Nepal who's growing gravity-resistant trees?
네팔의 한 마법사는 무중력 나무를 기른대
Neville, no offense, but I really don't care...
네빌, 미안한데 난 약초학엔
...about plants.
관심 없어
Now, if there's...
혹시 물속에서
I don't know about a turnip. But you could always use gillyweed.
약초는 몰라도 아가미 풀은 있지
- Any bets? Any bets? - Come on, place your bets!
- 내기 걸 사람? - 돈 놓고 돈 먹기!
Step up, mates! Don't be shy.
팍팍 걸어!
- Three lads. - One lady.
- 남자 셋 - 여자 하나!
- Four go down. - But do four come up?
- 그중 몇이... - 살아올까?
Don't be so mean.
돈 벌레들!
- Any bets? - Fleur's 10-1.
- 확률 100% - 플뢰르 10대 1!
- You're sure about this, Neville? - Absolutely.
- 확실해, 네빌? - 응!
- For an hour? - Most likely.
- 1시간? - 응, 대충...
Most likely?
대충?
Well, there is some debate among herbologists...
바닷물과 호수에서의 지속 시간이 다를 수도...
You're telling me this now? You must be joking!
그런 얘길 왜 이제야 해?
I just wanted to help.
난 그냥 돕고 싶어서...
Well, that makes you a right sight better than Ron and Hermione.
론과 헤르미온느보단 어쨌든 낫다
Where are they anyway?
걔들, 어디 간 거야?
- You seem a little tense, Harry. - Do I?
- 너 긴장한 것 같다 - 그래?
Welcome to the second task.
두 번째 과제입니다
Last night, something was stolen from each of our champions.
어젯밤, 각 챔피언의 보물이 하나씩
A treasure of sorts.
도난당했습니다
These four treasures, one for each champion...
그 보물들이 검은 호수 밑에 있습니다
In order to win...
그걸 찾아서
...each champion need only find their treasure and return to the surface.
물위로 올라오면 합격인데
- Simple enough, except for this: - Put that in your mouth.
- 조건이 있습니다 - 어서 삼켜
They will have but one hour to do so, and one hour only.
제한 시간이 딱 한시간입니다
After that, they'll be on their own. No magic will save them.
제한 시간 넘기면 마법을 못써요
You may begin at the sound of the cannon.
대포 쏘면 시작하세요
- What's the matter with him? - I don't know, I can't see him.
쟤 왜 저래?
Oh, my God. I've killed Harry Potter.
맙소사, 내가 해리를 죽였어!
What?
뭐야?
The Beauxbatons champion, Miss Delacour...
보바통 챔피언 플뢰르 양은 포기했으므로
...so she will take no further part in this task.
이번 과제에서 탈락입니다
But she's my friend too!
얘도 내 친구란 말야!
Only one!
한 명만 구해!
Let's get down below.
들어가 봅시다
Krum! Krum! Krum!
크룸! 크룸!
Yes!
좋았어!
Ascendio!
아센디오!
Harry!
해리!
He's all right.
무사해
He's all right. Barty!
수고했다... 바티!
- Go get him another towel. - I want all the judges over here now!
수건 더 가져와
You saved her, even though she wasn't yours to save.
넌 내 동생을 나대신 구했어
My little sister.
네 몫이 아닌데...
Thank you.
고마워
And you! You helped.
그리고 너! 너도 도와줬지?
Well, yeah, a bit.
뭐, 쫌 거들었지
- Harry! - Hermione!
- 해리! - 헤르미온느!
Are you all right? You must be freezing.
괜찮니? 춥겠다
Personally, I think you behaved admirably.
너 정말 멋있었어
I finished last, Hermione.
하지만 꼴찌야
Next to last. Fleur never got past the Grindylows.
세 번째야 플뢰르는 탈락했어
Krum! Krum! Krum!
크룸, 크룸!
Attention!
모두 주목!
The winner is Mr. Diggory...
우승자는 케드릭 디고리입니다
...who showed innate command of the Bubble-Head Charm.
거품 머리 마법을 잘 활용했죠
However, seeing as Mr. Potter would have finished first...
포터 군은 위즐리 군뿐 아니라
...had it not been for his determination to rescue not only Mr. Weasley...
딴 사람도 구하려다 1등을 놓쳤기에
...but the others as well, we've agreed to award him...
심사위원들의 긴급회의 끝에
...second place...
2위로 결정했습니다!
- Second place! - Well done!
2위래!
...for outstanding moral fiber!
희생정신을 높이 산 겁니다!
Yes!
좋았어!
- Right on. - All that moral fiber, eh?
- 멋지다 - 역시 대단해
Blimey. Even when you go wrong, it turns out right.
- 꼭 끝엔 스타 되더라 - 미스터 '희생정신'
Well done, boy.
훌륭해
- See you at Hagrid's, Harry. - I'm sorry we haven't spoken.
- 해그리드 집으로 와 - 만나고 싶었다
After all, your story is one I've heard so many times.
너에 관한 얘긴 많이 들었어
Quite remarkable, really. Tragic, of course...
사랑하는 가족을 잃는 건
...to lose one's family.
정말 큰 상처지
Never whole again, are we?
회복될 수 없는...
Still, life goes on...
하지만 이겨내야 돼
...and here we stand.
살아가야 하니까...
I'm sure your parents would be very proud of you today, Potter.
네 부모님이 무척 기뻐하실 게다
Bartemius!
바티, 앨 마법부의 견습 직원으로 뽑게?
The last boy who went into the Department of Mysteries never came out!
지난번 견습 직원은 실종됐다며?
And they say I'm mad.
진짜 미친 게 누군데!
Now, I remember... I remember when I first met you all.
너희를 처음 만난 날이 생각난다
Biggest bunch of misfits I ever set eyes on.
셋 다 걱정됐지 적응할지...
Suppose you remind me of meself a little.
꼭 날 보는 듯 했어
- And here we all are, four years later. - We're still a bunch of misfits.
헌데 벌써 4년이 흘렀어
And Harry, of course.
게다가 해리는
Soon to be the youngest Triwizard champion there's ever been!
곧 트리위저드 사상 최연소 우승자가 될 거야!
Hooray!
만세!
Hogwarts, Hogwarts Hoggy Warty Hogwarts
호기와티, 호그와트 마법을 가르쳐줘요
Mr. Crouch?
크라우치 씨?
A man has died here, Fudge. And he won't be the last. You must take action.
사람이 죽었네, 퍼지 시합을 취소하게
I will not.
안돼
In times like these, the wizard world looks to its leaders for strength, Dumbledore!
이럴 때일수록 강한 지도력을 보여야 돼!
Then for once show them some!
보여봐!
The Triwizard Tournament will not be canceled. I will not be seen as a coward!
취소는 못해! 겁쟁이 되긴 싫네
A true leader does what is right, no matter what others think.
남 눈치 보는 것도 겁쟁이야!
- What did you say to me? - Excuse me, gentlemen.
뭐 어째?
It may interest you to know this conversation is no longer private.
문 밖에 누가 온 것 같은데요
Oh, Harry!
해리, 정말 반갑구나!
I can come back later, professor.
나중에 올까요?
Not necessary, Harry. The minister and I are done. L'll be back in a moment.
아냐, 얘기 다 했다 금방 돌아오마
Minister, after you.
장관, 나가세
There you are. Your hat.
모자
Oh, Harry, do feel free to indulge in a little Licorice Snap in my absence.
감초 사탕이나 먹고 있으렴
But I have to warn you, they're a wee bit sharp.
사탕이 좀 사나우니 조심해
Professor?
교수님?
- Professor. - Yeah.
교수님
Igor Karkaroff, you have been brought from Azkaban at your own request...
카르카로프 증언할 게 있다고 해서
...to present evidence to this council.
널 아즈카반에서 데려왔다 증언이 진실이면
...council may be prepared to order your immediate release.
감형시켜 주겠다 그게 확인될 때까진
Until such time, you remain in the eyes of the Ministry a convicted Death Eater.
넌 '죽음을 먹는 자'로 죄수 신분이다
Do you accept these terms?
동의하는가?
- I do, sir. - And what do you wish to present?
- 네 - 말할 게 뭔가?
I have names, sir.
제 동료들 이름입니다
There was Rosier, Evan Rosier.
에반 로시에도 단원이었어요
- Rosier is dead. - He took a piece of me with him...
그는 죽었다
- Lf that is all the witness has to offer... - No, no, no.
그게 전부면...
There was Rookwood! He was a spy.
록우드도 있어요 첩자였죠!
Augustus Rookwood? Of the Department of Mysteries?
미스테리 부의 록우드?
Yeah, the same.
네
He passed information to You-Know-Who from inside the Ministry itself.
내부 정보를 '그 사람'에게 줬죠
Very well. Council will deliberate.
좋아 감형을 논의할 테니
In the meantime, you will return to Azkaban.
아즈카반에서 기다려
No! Wait! Wait, please! Please, I have more! What about Snape? Severus Snape?
잠깐만, 또 있어요! 세베루스 스네이프!
As the council is aware, I've given evidence on this matter.
스네이프 교수도 한때
Severus Snape was indeed a Death Eater and, prior to Lord Voldemort's downfall...
'죽음을 먹는 자'였지만
- Today he's no more a Death Eater than I am. - Snape remains faithful to the Dark Lord!
- 우리 편이요! - '그'의 부하요!
Silence!
조용!
Unless the witness possesses any genuine name of consequence...
믿을 만한 증언이 더 이상 없다면
...this session is now concluded.
청문회를 마치겠다
Oh, no, no, no.
안돼요, 잠깐만...
I've heard about one more.
말할 게 또 있소
- What's that? - The name.
- 뭔가? - 이름이요!
- Yes? - I know for a fact...
누구지?
...and, by means of the Cruciatus Curse...
오러인, 프랭크 롱바텀과 그 부인을 고문한 자요!
The name. Give me the wretched name!
그놈이 누구냐구?
Barty Crouch...
바티 크라우치...
...Junior.
2세요!
Hold him down!
꽉 잡아!
Get your filthy hands off me, you pathetic little men!
이 손 못 놔? 더러운 것들!
Hello, Father.
안녕, 아버지
You are no son of mine.
넌 내 아들 아냐
Curiosity is not a sin, Harry. But you should exercise caution.
호기심은 죄가 아니지만 신중해야 돼
It's a Pensieve.
펜시브란 거다
Very useful if, like me, you find your mind a wee bit stretched.
머리가 복잡할 때 지난 일을 다시 보며
It allows me to see once more things I've already seen.
생각을 정리하는데 도움을 줘
You see, Harry, I have searched and searched for something...
난 요즘 뭔가를 찾고 있다
...some small detail...
무심코 지나친
...something I might have overlooked...
과거의 어떤 부분...
...something that would explain why these terrible things have happened.
그걸 찾아야 모든 의문이 풀릴 텐데
Every time I get close to an answer, it slips away.
답이 잡힐 듯 하면서도 안 잡혀!
It's maddening.
미치겠다
Sir? Mr. Crouch's son.
크라우치 씨의 아들은
What exactly happened to him?
그 후 어떻게 됐죠?
He was sent to Azkaban. Destroyed Barty to do it.
아즈카반에 갇혔지 바티는 괴로웠지만
But he had no choice. The evidence was overwhelming.
어쩔 수 없었어 증거가 확실해서...
- Why do you ask? - It's just that I...
왜 묻니?
I had a dream about him.
그의 꿈을 꿨거든요
It was in the summer, before school.
여름방학 때였어요
In the dream, I was in a house.
전 어떤 집에 있었죠
And voldemort was there, only he wasn't quite human.
볼드모트도 있었는데 사람이 아니었어요
And Wormtail was there too. And Mr. Crouch's son.
웜테일과 바티 2세도 있었죠
- Have there been others like this dream? - Yes.
그런 꿈 자주 꾸니?
Always the same one.
늘 같은 꿈이에요
Sir, these dreams...
꿈에서 본 일이
...what I see, you don't think it's actually happening, do you?
설마 현실에서도 일어나진 않겠죠?
I think it's unwise for you to linger over these dreams, Harry.
꿈은 단순한 꿈일 뿐이야
I think it's best if you simply...
걱정하지 마
...cast them away.
머리에서 지워
It's a sign, Severus. You know what it means as well as I.
스네이프 이 표식, 너도 알 텐데!
Potter!
포터!
What's your hurry?
잠깐만 나 좀 볼까?
Congratulations, your performance in the Black Lake was inspiring.
검은 호수에서 활약이 눈부시더군
Gillyweed, am I correct?
아가미 풀을 썼지?
Yes, sir.
네
Ingenious.
대단하구나
A rather rare herb, gillyweed.
그거 흔한 식물이 아닌데...
Not something found in your everyday garden.
쉽게 구하기 힘든 거야
Nor is this.
이것도 그렇지
Know what it is?
뭔지 아니?
Bubble juice, sir?
거품 주스인가요?
Veritaserum.
베리타세룸이다
Three drops of this and You-Know-Who himself would spill his darkest secrets.
이거 세 방울이면 '그'도 모든 걸 불지
The use of it on a student is, regrettably, forbidden. However...
학생에게 사용하는 건 금지돼 있지만
...should you ever steal from my personal stores again...
네가 또 내 약장에 손을 대면
...my hand might just slip over your morning pumpkin juice.
나도 몰래 네 주스에 이걸 탈지 몰라
- I haven't stolen anything. - Don't lie to me.
- 전 훔친 거 없어요 - 날 속일 생각 마라
Gillyweed may be innocuous, but boomslang skin, lacewing flies?
아가미 풀은 독성이 없지만 아프리카 뱀과 풀잠자리는 달라
You and your little friends are brewing Polyjuice Potion, and believe me...
너희가 왜 폴리 주스를 만드는지
...l'm going to find out why!
꼭 밝혀낼 테다!
Sonorus!
조용!
Earlier today, Professor Moody placed the Triwizard Cup deep within the maze.
무디 교수가 우승컵을 미로에 숨겨놨습니다
Only he knows its exact position. Now, as Mr. Diggory...
위치는 아무도 모릅니다 디고리 군과
...and Mr. Potter...
포터 군은
...are tied for first position...
동점 선두이므로
...they will be the first to enter the maze, followed by Mr. Krum...
먼저 출발하고 크룸 군
...and Miss Delacour. - Come on! Krum! Krum! Krum!
델라쿠르 양이 뒤따릅니다
The first person to touch the cup will be the winner!
컵을 먼저 찾으면 우승입니다!
I've instructed the staff to patrol the perimeter.
도전을 포기하고 싶을 땐
Should, at any point, a contestant wish to withdraw from the task...
지팡이로 불꽃을 쏴올려서
...he or she need only send up red sparks with their wands.
미로 밖의 순찰팀을 부르면 됩니다
Contestants! Gather around. Quickly!
선수들 모이세요 빨리!
In the maze, you'll find no dragons or creatures of the deep.
미로 속엔 용도 호수의 괴물도 없다
Instead, you'll face something even more challenging.
대신, 더 무서운 게 있지
You see, people change in the maze.
미로에선 사람들이 변해
Oh, find the cup if you can.
우승컵 찾다가
But be very wary, you could just lose yourselves along the way.
자기 자신을 잃을 수 있다는 걸 명심해
Champions, prepare yourselves!
챔피언들!
Good luck.
잘해라
- My boy. - See you later, Dad.
다녀올게요
On the count of three. One...
셋을 셉니다
Fleur?
플뢰르?
Periculum!
페리쿨럼!
Expelliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스!
No, don't! Stop! He's bewitched, Cedric!
안돼! 크룸은 마법에 걸렸어
- Get off me! - He's bewitched!
- 놔! - 정상이 아냐!
Yes.
좋았어
Harry!
해리!
Reducto!
레둑토!
- Thanks. - No problem.
고맙다
You know, for a moment there, I thought you were gonna let it get me.
잠깐 겁먹었었어 날 두고 갈까봐...
For a moment, so did I.
그러려고 했어
Some game, huh?
살벌하네
Some game.
그러게
Go!
뛰어!
Go on, take it. You saved me, take it!
네가 집어!
- Together. One, two... - Two...
같이 집어 하나, 둘...
...three!
셋!
- You okay? - Yeah. You?
괜찮니?
Where are we?
여긴 어디지?
I've been here before.
낯익은 데야
It's a Portkey.
포트키였군!
- Harry, the cup is a Portkey. - I've been here before, in a dream.
- 우승컵이 포트키야! - 꿈속에서 여기 와봤어
Cedric! We have to get back to the cup. Now!
케드릭 컵을 잡아, 빨리!
What are you talking about?
왜 그래?
- Harry! What is it? - Get back to the cup!
- 왜 그래? - 컵을 붙잡아!
- Who are you? What do you want? - Kill the spare.
넌 누구야?
- Avada Kedavra! - No! Cedric!
- 아바다 케다브라! - 안돼!
Do it! Now!
빨리 해!
Bone of the father...
자신도 모르게 바쳐진 아버지의 뼈여
Flesh of the servant...
이 종의 살을
...willingly sacrificed.
기꺼이 바치노라
And blood of the enemy...
강제로 빼앗은
...forcibly taken.
원수의... 피가
The Dark Lord shall rise...
어둠의 마왕을
...again.
부활시키리라!
My wand, Wormtail.
내 지팡이를 다오
Hold out your arm.
팔을 내밀어라
Master.
주인님
Thank you, master.
감사합니다
The other arm, Wormtail.
반대쪽 팔!
Welcome, my friends.
나의 친구들이여!
Thirteen years it's been, and yet...
13년이나 흘렀지만
...here you stand before me as though it were only yesterday.
마치 어제 헤어진 듯 반갑구나
I confess myself...
하지만 솔직히...
...disappointed.
실망했다
Not one of you tried to find me.
아무도 날 안 찾더군
Crabbe! Macnair!
크레이브!
Goyle!
고일!
Not even you...
넌 믿었는데...
...Lucius.
루시우스
My Lord, had I detected any sign, a whisper of your whereabouts...
주인님
There were signs, my slippery friend. And more than whispers.
핑계대지 마라 표식은 많았어
I assure you, my Lord, I have never renounced the old ways.
전 어둠의 마법을 저버리지 않았습니다
The face I have been obliged to present each day since your absence...
주인님이 사라지신 후 다른 얼굴로 살아왔지만
...that is my true mask.
그건 가면이었습니다
I returned.
전 돌아왔습니다
Out of fear, not loyalty.
충성심이 아닌 두려움 때문이지
Still, you have proved yourself useful these past few months, Wormtail.
어쨌든
Thank you, master.
감사합니다, 주인님!
Thank you.
감사합니다!
- Such a handsome boy. - Don't touch him!
인물이 아깝군
Harry.
해리
I'd almost forgotten you were here.
네가 있는 걸 깜빡했다
Standing on the bones of my father. Yeah.
넌 내 아버지 무덤 위에 서있어
I'd introduce you...
소개는 생략하지 너도 나만큼 유명해졌으니까...
The boy who lived.
살아남은 소년!
How lies have fed your legend, Harry.
네 신화는 거짓투성이야
Shall I reveal what really happened that night 13 years ago?
13년 전 그날의 진실을 말해줄까?
Shall I divulge how I truly lost my powers?
내가 어떻게 힘을 잃었는지 말해줘?
Yes, shall I?
그건... 사랑 때문이었어
You see, when dear, sweet Lily Potter gave her life for her only son...
엄마인 릴리 포터가 아들 대신 죽을 때
...she provided the ultimate protection.
애한테 보호막을 쳐놔서
I could not touch him.
건들 수가 없었지
It was old magic.
낡은 마법인데
Something I should have foreseen.
내가 방심했어
But no matter, no matter.
하지만 상관없어
Things have changed.
이젠 상황이 달라
I can touch you...
난 널 만질 수 있어!
now
이젠!
Astonishing what a few drops of your blood will do, eh, Harry?
네 피 몇 방울의 힘이 대단하지?
Pick up your wand, Potter.
지팡이를 들어라!
I said, pick it up! Get up! Get up!
지팡이 들라구! 일어나!
You've been taught how to duel, I presume, yes?
결투하는 법은 배웠겠지?
First, we bow to each other.
먼저 서로 절하고! 뭐해? 예법은 지켜야지
Dumbledore wouldn't want you to forget your manners, would he?
덤블도어한테 여태 뭘 배웠냐?
I said, bow.
절하란 말이다!
- That's better. And now... - No.
좋아, 시작해볼까?
Crucio!
크루시오!
Attaboy, Harry.
제법인데, 해리?
Your parents would be proud.
네 부모가 기뻐하겠군
Especially your filthy Muggle mother.
특히 천한 머글인 네 에미가!
Expelliar...
엑스펠...
I'm going to kill you, Harry Potter.
죽여주마 해리 포터
I'm going to destroy you.
끝장내주겠어
After tonight, no one will ever again question my powers.
오늘 이후로
After tonight, if they speak of you...
오늘 이후로
...begged for death.
죽음을 애걸하던 너와
And I, being a merciful Lord...
자비롭게 그 소원을
...obliged.
들어준 나를...
Get up!
일어나!
Don't you turn your back on me, Harry Potter!
내게 등 돌리지 마!
I want you to look at me when I kill you!
네 눈에서 생명의 빛이 꺼져가는 걸 봐야겠다!
Have it your way.
소원이라면!
- Expelliarmus! - Avada Kedavra!
- 엑스펠리아르무스! - 아바다 케다브라!
Do nothing! He's mine to finish!
넌 빠져! 내가 죽이겠다!
He's mine!
빠지라구!
Harry, when the connection is broken, you must get to the Portkey.
이 빛이 끊어지면 포트키로 달려가!
We can linger for a moment to give you some time...
우린 잠시의 시간밖엔 벌어줄 수 없다!
Harry, take my body back, will you?
해리
Take my body back to my father.
날 아버지에게 보내줘
Let go.
이제 가
Sweetheart, you're ready.
해리, 지금이야!
Let go! Let go!
어서 가, 어서!
Accio!
아씨오!
No!
안돼!
He did it!
이겼다!
Harry!
해리!
No! No! No, don't!
놔요, 놔요!
For God's sake, Dumbledore, what's happened?
이게 어떻게 된 건가?
He's back. He's back.
그가 돌아왔어요! 볼드모트가 돌아왔다구요!
Cedric, he asked me to bring his body back.
케드릭만 거기 두고 혼자 올 수가 없었어요
It's all right, Harry. It's all right.
진정해라, 괜찮아
He's home. You both are.
둘 다 돌아왔잖니
Keep everybody in their seats. A boy has just been killed.
모두 앉혀요! 사망자가 있소
The body must be moved, Dumbledore. There are too many people.
시신을 치워야 돼 애들이 못 보게...
Let me through.
비켜봐요
Let me through!
비켜봐!
That's my son!
걘 내 아들이요!
That's my boy!
내 아들이 죽다니!
Lt's my boy!
내 아들이!
- Come on. Get up. Easy, easy! - No.
이리와
This is not where you want to be right now. Come on.
- 일단 좀 들어가자 - 안돼요!
Lt's all right, I got you.
괜찮아, 내게 의지해
I got you. Come on. Easy, now.
부축해 줄게 어서 가자
Are you all right, Potter?
괜찮니, 포터?
Does it hurt? That?
다친 데 아프냐?
Not so much now.
많이 나아졌어요
Perhaps I'd better take a look at it.
그래도 좀 보자
The cup was a Portkey.
컵이 포트키였어요
Someone had bewitched it.
누가 손 댄 거죠
What was it like?
어떻든?
- What was he like? - Who?
- 만나보니까... - 누구요?
The Dark Lord.
어둠의 마왕!
What was it like to stand in his presence?
그의 앞에 선 기분이 어떻든?
I don't know.
모르겠어요
It was like I'd fallen into one of my dreams...
그냥 꿈꾸는 것 같았어요
...into one of my nightmares.
늘 꾸는 악몽...
Were there others?
또 누가 있든?
In the graveyard, were there others?
묘지에 말이야
I don't think I said anything about a graveyard, professor.
묘지에 갔었단 얘긴 안했는데요
"Marvelous creatures, dragons, aren't they?"
'용은 참 근사한 동물이지?'
Did you think that miserable oaf would've led you into the woods...
내 충고가 없었으면 그 바보가 널 숲에 데려갔을까?
Do you think Cedric Diggory would've told you to open the egg underwater...
내 귀띔이 없었으면 케드릭이 어떻게
...if I hadn't told him first myself?
알 여는 법을 알았겠냐?
Did you think Neville Longbottom, the witless wonder...
내가 네빌에게 책을 안 줬으면
...could've provided you with gillyweed if I hadn't given him the book...
아가미 풀에 대해 걔가 어떻게 알았겠어?
Lt was you from the beginning. You put my name in the Goblet of Fire.
당신이었군
You ended up in that graveyard tonight because it was meant to be so.
넌 각본에 따라 묘지로 간 거라구
And now the deed is done.
이제 다 이뤘어
The blood that runs through these veins runs within the Dark Lord.
그 분의 몸속엔 네 피가 흐르고 있지
Imagine how he will reward me when he learns...
내가 해리 포터를 없앴다는 걸
...that I have once and for all...
그 분이 아시면
...silenced the great Harry Potter.
내게 큰 상을 내리실 게다!
Expelliarmus!
엑스펠리아르무스!
Severus.
스네이프!
That's it, take it.
삼켜
- Do you know who I am? - Albus Dumbledore.
내가 누구지?
- Are you Alastor Moody? Are you? - No.
- 넌 앨러스터 무디냐? - 아냐
Is he in this room? Ls he in this room?
무디는 어딨지? 이 방에 있나?
Harry, away from there!
해리, 이리 나와!
- You all right, Alastor? - I'm sorry, Albus.
괜찮소, 무디 교수?
That's Moody. But then who's...?
저 분이 무디 교수면...
Polyjuice Potion.
폴리 주스군요
Now we know who's been stealing from your stores, Severus.
약장 턴 범인은 따로 있었군
We'll get you up in a minute.
금방 꺼내주겠소!
Harry!
해리!
Barty Crouch Junior.
바티 크라우치 2세
L'll show you mine if you show me yours.
네 팔을 보여주면 나도 보여주지
Your arm, Harry.
팔을 보여줘
You know what this means, don't you?
그 상처의 의미 알지?
He's back.
그가 왔어
Lord Voldemort has returned.
볼드모트 경이 돌아왔다구!
I'm sorry, sir. I couldn't help it.
어쩔 수가 없었어요
Send an owl to Azkaban. I think they'll find they're missing a prisoner.
아즈카반에 연락해요 탈옥수를 잡았다고...
- L'll be welcomed back like a hero. - Perhaps.
- 난 그들의 영웅이야 - 영웅?
Personally, I've never had much time for heroes.
그 단어를 더럽히지 마
Today, we acknowledge...
오늘 우리는
...a really terrible loss.
한 학생을 잃었습니다
Cedric Diggory was, as you all know...
케드릭 디고리는 성실한 모범생이었습니다
...infinitely fair-minded...
늘 공명정대했고
...and, most importantly...
신의를 지킬 줄 알았던
...a fierce, fierce friend.
멋진 정의파 학생이었죠
Now, I think, therefore, you have the right to know exactly how he died.
그가 어떻게 죽었는지 다들 알아야 합니다
You see...
케드릭은...
...Cedric Diggory was murdered...
살해당했습니다!
...by Lord Voldemort!
볼드모트 경에게!
The Ministry of Magic does not wish me to tell you this.
마법부는 비밀로 하길 원했으나
But not to do so, I think, would be an insult to his memory.
그건 케드릭을 욕되게 하는 겁니다
Now, the pain...
그의 죽음에
...we all feel at this dreadful loss reminds me...
모두가 슬퍼함을 보면서
...and reminds us...
전 느낍니다
...that while we may come from different places and speak in different tongues...
우린 비록 문화도 언어도 다르지만
...our hearts beat as one.
뛰는 맥박은 똑같다는 걸!
In light of recent events...
이런 상황에선
...the bonds of friendship we've made this year will be more important than ever.
세 학교의 단합이 어느 때보다 중요합니다
Remember that, and Cedric Diggory will not have died in vain.
그의 죽음을 헛되게 해선 안됩니다
You remember that...
그 점을 명심할 때
...and we'll celebrate a boy who was...
정직하고 용감했던 케드릭은
...kind and honest...
우리 마음속에
...and brave and true, right to the very end.
언제까지나 살아있을 것입니다
I never liked these curtains.
이 커튼, 늘 싫었어
Set them on fire in my fourth year.
4학년 때 불에 태웠지
By accident, of course.
물론 사고로...
I put you in terrible danger this year, Harry. I'm sorry.
널 위험에 빠뜨렸던 거 정말 미안하다
Professor...
교수님
...when I was in the graveyard, there was a moment...
그날 밤 볼드모트 지팡이가
...when Voldemort's wand and mine sort of connected.
잠시 제 지팡이와 교감한 듯 했어요
Priori Incantatem.
프리오리 인칸타템...
You saw your parents that night, didn't you?
부모님을 봤다고 했지?
They reappeared.
그날 밤에...
No spell can reawaken the dead, Harry. I trust you know that.
어떤 주문도 죽은 자는 못 깨워
Dark and difficult times lie ahead.
곧 큰 시련이 닥칠게다
Soon we must all face the choice between what is right and what is easy.
옳은 것과 쉬운 것 중 한쪽을 택해야 할 때가...
But remember this:
허나 명심해 네겐 친구들이 있어
You're not alone.
넌 혼자가 아냐
Hermione.
헤르미온느!
This is for you.
내 주소야
Write to me. Promise.
꼭 편지해
Bye.
안녕
Au revoir, Ron.
안녕, 론
Do you think we'll ever just have a quiet year at Hogwarts?
호그와트에도 조용한 날이 올까?
- No.
안 올걸?
No, I didn't think so. Oh, well. What's life without a few dragons?
하긴 사고가 많아야 스릴 있지
Everything's going to change now, isn't it?
이젠 모든 게 예전 같지 않겠지?
Yes.
그래
Promise you'll write this summer. Both of you.
이번 방학엔 둘 다 편지해
I won't. You know I won't.
싫어, 내가 미쳤냐?
- Harry will, won't you? - Yeah. Every week.
해리, 넌 쓸 거지?